{"tossups": [{"question": "In one battle fought in this state, British forces led by Charles Mawhood surrounded and killed Hugh Mercer after mistaking him for George Washington. At another battle in this state, the actions of Mary Hays may have inspired popular accounts of Molly Pitcher. The Hessian commander Johann Rall was killed at another battle fought in this state in December 1776 that was preceded by Washington\u2019s crossing of the Delaware. For ten points, name this state home to the Revolutionary War battles of Princeton and Trenton.", "answer": "<b> New Jersey</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One man involved in this event had previously fled to Paterborn and requested reinstatement from the subject of this event. Empress Irene of Constantinople was de-legitimized after this event, and Einhard declared that its subject would \u201cnot have set foot\u201d in St. Peter\u2019s Basilica had he known what would take place. This event took place on Christmas Day, 800. For ten points, name this ceremony in which Pope Leo III created the Holy Roman Empire by elevating the son of Pepin the Short to the throne.", "answer": "<b> Crowning</b> of<b> Charlemagne</b> (accept<b> Coronation</b> of<b> Charlemagne</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This country\u2019s current President led a 1983 coup against Shehu Shagari. Abubakar Shekau leads a terrorist organization based in this country, which in 2014 attacked a school in Chibok, abducting 276 girls. Muhammad Buhari replaced Goodluck Jonathan as this country\u2019s President in 2015. For ten points, name this African country where, in 2011, Boko Haram bombed a UN compound in Abuja.", "answer": "<b> Nigeria</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "This man was the first athlete to run for 2,000 yards in an NFL season in 1973. He had to auction his 1968 Heisman Trophy, earned at USC, to pay the estate of Ronald Goldman as a result of a civil suit in 1997, two years after Alan Dershowitz and Johnnie Cochran defended this man in the \u201cTrial of the Century\u201d. For ten points, name this former Buffalo Bill running back who was acquitted of murdering his ex-wife, Nicole Brown, in 1995.", "answer": "Orenthal James \u201cO.J.\u201d<b> Simpson</b> Page 1", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s doctoral thesis studied the degree of brain myelinization in white rats. With Harvey Karr, this man conditioned rats to run into walls when food was moved from its previous location in a maze. This engineer of the Kerplunk! experiment supposedly invented the coffee break in an ad campaign. With Rosalie Rayner, he conditioned a nine-month old boy to fear furry objects in the \u201cLittle Albert\u201dexperiment. For ten points, name this American psychologist who founded the school of behaviorism.", "answer": "John Broadus<b> Watson</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {"question": "Folk singer Dave van Ronk was arrested during this event. The Mattachine Society tried to control rioting after this event. Allen Ginsberg said that some protesters during this event had \u201clost that wounded look\u201d. The death of Judy Garland has been proposed as a starting point for this event. An NYPD raid on a bar triggered, for ten points, what series of riots in Greenwich Village in 1969 that began the modern gay rights movement?", "answer": "<b> Stonewall</b> (Inn) riots (or the raid on the<b> Stonewall</b> Inn itself)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Miguel Barbachano advocated for this state\u2019s independence until a Caste War against Mayan forces, which included a sacking of its city of Valladolid [vay-yah-doh-leed]. Studies in the 1970s found shocked quartz in the northern area of this state, centered near the city of Chicxulub [chick-shu-lub] and dating to the K-Pg boundary. This Mexican state, with capital Merida, is the hypothesized site of the impact that killed the dinosaurs. For ten points, name this Mexican state on a namesake peninsula that juts into the Gulf of Mexico.", "answer": "<b> Yucatan</b> (or<b> Yucatan</b> Peninsula; do not accept Mexico)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Another champion of this sport refused to join the military during the Vietnam War, citing his Muslim beliefs. For ten points, name this sport whose champions have included Muhammad Ali.", "answer": "<b> boxing</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A \u201cre-education movement\u201d by one side after this war killed over 100,000 suspected collaborators in the Bodo League massacre. The Hangang Bridge was destroyed during this conflict by one side to prevent an offensive, leading to the deaths of over 1,000 refugees. Aerial combat in this war took place over MiG Alley, and American entrance into this war led to heavy casualties at the Battles of Heartbreak Ridge and Pork Chop Hill. For ten points, name this 1950 to 1953 war that was ended by an armistice which established a demilitarized zone on its namesake peninsula.", "answer": "<b> Korea</b>n War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "During the Vietnam War, Tony Shafrazi defaced this painting with the phrase \u201cKILL LIES ALL.\u201d A tapestry of this work commissioned by Nelson Rockefeller was covered during a Colin Powell speech at the United Nations building. A naked lightbulb illuminates this work, in which a flower grows out of a hand clutching a broken sword below a bull and a screaming horse. For ten points, name this large Pablo Picasso painting created in response to the bombing of a namesake town during the Spanish Civil War.", "answer": "<b> Guernica</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man commissioned Victor Baltard to renovate the market of Les Halles, and this man supported the Perriere brothers in forming the Cr\u00b4edit Mobilier. Derided by Victor Hugo, this man was inspired by Hyde Park to refurbish the Bois de Boulogne and the Bois de Vincennes as part of this man\u2019s renovation of his capital, supervised by Baron Haussmann. This supporter of Emperor Maximilian of Mexico would be forced to abdicate after surrendering at the Battle of Sedan. For ten points, name this last emperor of France, nephew to the first.", "answer": "<b> Napol\u00b4eon III</b> (or<b> Louis-Napol\u00b4eon</b> Bonaparte, do not accept or prompt on Napol\u00b4eon)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>One country launched the Mega Rice Project on this island, resulting in the mass drainage of its peat swamps. The southern portion of this island is referred to as (+) Kalimantan, and the Wallace line separates this island from Sulawesi. The Crocker Range is home to Mount (*)</b> Kinabalu, its highest point. The Philippines once claimed the province of Sabah on, for ten points, what island divided between Indonesia, Brunei and Malaysia?", "answer": "<b> Borneo</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This composer wrote a study for 23 strings in response to the destruction of the Munich Opera House and firebombing of Dresden. This composer of</b><em><b> Metamorphosen</b></em><b> spent two</b> <b>years as the head of the State Music Bureau for the (+)</b> <b>Nazis.</b> <b>He depicted a German</b> <b>trickster folk hero in the tone poem Till Eulenspiegel, while another of his works opens with the \u201cSunrise\u201d fanfare and includes sections titled after chapters of a (*) </b> Friedrich Nietzsche book. For ten points, what German composer wrote<em> Also Sprach Zarathustra</em>?", "answer": "Richard<b> Strauss</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This politician\u2019s \u201cSyracuse speech\u201d defended the Fugitive Slave Law in the Compromise of 1850, earning him ire from Horace Mann. His \u201cPlea for Harmony and Peace\u201d speech was</b> <b>defended by John F. Kennedy in</b><em><b> Profiles in Courage</b></em><b>. The (+)</b> <b>defended by John F. Kennedy in</b><em><b> Profiles in Courage</b></em><b>. The (+)</b> <b>defended by John F. Kennedy in</b><em><b> Profiles in Courage</b></em><b>. The (+)</b> <b>Know-Nothing Party put</b> <b>this man\u2019s name on the ballot in the 1852 election.</b> <b>this man\u2019s name on the ballot in the 1852 election.</b> <b>This senator, who declared \u201cLiberty</b> <b>This senator, who declared \u201cLiberty</b> <b>and Union, (*)</b> now and forever, one and inseparable,\u201d signed a treaty setting Maine\u2019s border with now and forever, one and inseparable,\u201d signed a treaty setting Maine\u2019s border with now and forever, one and inseparable,\u201d signed a treaty setting Maine\u2019s border with Baron Ashburton. For ten points, name this Massachusetts orator who formed the Great Triumvirate with Calhoun and Clay.", "answer": "Daniel<b> Webster</b> Page 9", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The original recitation of this work supposedly caused one listener to faint upon hearing the name of her son, Marcellus, mentioned. The executors of this work were ordered to publish this work after its author\u2019s death, regardless of his wishes, and this work\u2019s patron</b> <b>was the nobleman (+)</b> <b>Maecenas. This work\u2019s title figure wins the hand of Lavinia after</b> <b>defeating Turnus, and (*)</b> Augustus championed this work because he saw himself as an incarnate of its hero, who escaped from the Trojan War. For ten points, name this epic poem by Virgil about the title Trojan prince.", "answer": "The<b> Aeneid</b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Arthur Laffer attributed his famous curve to a writer in this language, who posited</b> <b>that empires lose group solidarity in the face of attacks by nomads. The book</b><em><b> The</b></em> <em><b>Incoherence of the</b></em><b> (+)</b> <em><b>Philosophers</b></em><b> attacked several authors who wrote in this</b> <b>language; one author attacked by that volume wrote</b><em><b> The Book of Healing</b></em><b>. Authors</b> <b>writing in this language include (*)</b> al-Ghazali. For ten points, name this Semitic language, used by Avicenna and throughout the Middle East.", "answer": "<b> Arabic</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}], "bonuses": []}